(LIGHT GIGGLE)
Mr. and Mrs. Taylor,
it's lovely to meet you.
What a wonderful party.
(INAUDIBLE)
I almost forgot.
I almost forgot!
Happy anniversary.
Wow, 25 years.
It's quite an accomplishment.
(OLDER WOMAN)
"I am neither liberal
nor conservative.
I prefer to be a free artist,
and nothing more.
Free from violence and lies."
Chekhov wrote about the human
condition, the absurdity of it.
The pain that arises
when people who have...
clung to their habits
and their delusions...
are forced to confront a reality
that contradicts
their world view.
Does that sound familiar
to anyone in here?
- (WOMAN) Yeah, I think it does.
- (MAN) Of course.
- America today, perhaps?
- (CLASS LAUGHS)
(MAN) Table for four.
(HOSTESS) Welcome, gentlemen.
Afternoon, Senators Coyle, Hunt.
Paul, you studied in Lyon under
Bocuse, so this should be good.
We're deadlocked. Settle this.
Old school pizza joints.
- Chicago vs New York.
- Malnati's or Patsy's?
But choose wisely, a floor vote
hangs in the balance.
(RESTAURANT CHATTER)
- Malnati's for the sauce.
- Bring on the filibuster.
Patsy's for the crust.
Food is the great equalizer.
(MAN) Yeah, I got you.
This one's going in the kitchen.
(WOMAN)
Two more and that's it, yeah.
(TRUNK CLOSES)
Babe, why can't we sit
with your parents?
I told you, babe,
it's literally one long table.
(SIGHS)
- (PAUL) Hey, guys, come on in.
- Hi!
- Ellen, a minute?
- Oh, hi. Walk with me.
I want to get out
before L Street's a clog.
Listen, um,
Dean Scanlin wants to
address this hysteria...
about Ivy Leagues being bastions
for radicalized liberalism.
We're not Ivy League.
This is why he feels
our university is
best positioned to comment.
(CHUCKLES)
I feel a trap coming on.
The Sunday morning news shows.
I know it's a big weekend
and the kids are all coming,
but the shows
can do it remotely.
Just don't hand me
talking points, Jim, okay?
I'll speak
in my own words, okay?
How are we doing
with the catering, Rana?
Everything is on schedule.
- (PEOPLE LAUGHING)
- So, how's the speech coming?
Turns out menu writing
is where my talent ends.
(MAN VOICE ON COMPUTER)
Ladies and gentlemen,
- Anna Taylor!
- (CROWD CHEERING)
(ANNA) Oh, my God!
Hello!
(CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
Hi, everybody. How you doing?
You sexy motherfuckers,
look at you.
Hello! Sit the fuck down.
- (SHUTTER CLICKS)
- Okay, got it?
- Thank you.
- Okay.
(SIGHS) Oh, my God.
(GROUP CHUCKLING)
Oh, hey, come here.
(QUIETLY)
Come on. Come on, don't be shy.
(GRUNTS)
Thank you. How you doing?
(LOUD KISS)
- You okay? You sure?
- Yeah. Yeah. How you feeling?
- Yeah.
- Ready?
- Do I look okay?
- Yeah, you look beautiful.
- You're not nervous, are you?
- No. You?
No. No, it's gonna be fun.
Yeah.
(COMPACT CLICKS)
You all right?
(HUSHED) I'm glad
we went with the jacket.
Yeah, me, too.
- (SIGHS) You excited?
- Kind of. You seem nervous.
No, I'm okay.
- I'm gonna get us some drinks.
- Okay.
I'll be right back.
(SCATTERED LAUGHING)
(LIGHT MUSIC PLAYS)
(KNOCKING)
(ANNA)
Bird girl, are you here?
- (LAUGHING)
- Hey!
- Oh, my bird girl! Hi!
- I missed you!
I missed you, too.
You look great.
I got you something.
Here, check it out.
- (MURMURS)
- (GIGGLES)
Mmm.
Okay, so this...
is one of the most subversive
satires ever written.
It is a "fuck you"
to the system,
if you couldn't tell.
- The reason I do comedy.
- It's so sick.
- You like it?
- I love it.
(CHUCKLES)
I think you need something else
on your walls
besides like anime and...
You have so many leaves, Birdie.
Got some pictures.
So, what's happening?
What's going on?
Tell me everything.
Josh brought the new girlfriend.
And, um, Aunt Paula is not here,
but she just got out
of the hospital, so...
- Was she sick?
- Eh, I mean, kind of.
She had a nervous breakdown
after Uncle Tommy watched
an octopus documentary
and moved to a kelp forest
in Tasmania.
- Wait. What?
- (WHISPERS) That's her.
I gotta write this shit down.
(CHATTERING)
(QUIETLY) Hey.
- Ready to go?
- Yeah.
- (CLEARS THROAT)
- (OLDER WOMAN) Hello!
Mama! Hi!
- Oh, I missed you.
- Look at you! Wow!
- Mom, you look fabulous.
- Come here.
Hi, Dad. Oh.
How are you guys?
See your sister?
- (MOM) Did you see the sign?
- Happy anniversary!
- Love it.
- Love the sign, Bird.
I gotta get one of those.
Hey, hey, hey!
See ya! (LAUGHS)
- Hi! How are you?
- Hi!
- Hi! Hey.
- Hi.
It's an interesting...
- weapon you're wearing.
- Weaponry.
(ANNA)
Have you met the girlfriend?
(CYNTHIA) Yosh's new girl?
- He's making a move.
- She doesn't blink.
- (ANNA) That's unsettling.
- Hi.
Honey...
- I didn't see you come in!
- Mmm. Hey, Mom.
- How was the commute?
- It was fine.
- Hey, Dad. Good to see you.
- How are you? Good to see you.
- Guys, this is Liz.
- Ha.
It's lovely to meet you,
Mr. and Mrs. Taylor.
Uh, very nice to meet you, Liz.
- Uh, Paul and Ellen, please.
- Oh.
It's a wonderful party.
Yeah, you guys killed it again.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Happy anniversary.
(PAUL) Thank you.
25 years is quite
an accomplishment.
(GROANS)
She tolerates me on most days.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
Well, you have
a beautiful family.
Only child here, by way
of a nasty Midwest divorce.
- Mmm.
It's fine.
The rage fuels the writing.
(LIGHT CHUCKLE)
- So, you're a writer.
- Yes, that's-that's how we met.
Yeah, we have the same agent.
(SIGHS) Christmas party.
She seems nice...
if you get past
the Seventh Day Adventist vibe.
Just think,
seems like only yesterday
he was so mad at us he ran away
to the International Spy Museum.
- Nobody told me that.
- I forgot about that.
Yeah. Remember that?
What sort of writing
do you do, Liz?
Oh, well, I've been working
on a self-organizing guide.
Our new world through
a fresh prism.
That sounds important.
She's being modest, too.
It's brilliant.
It is.
I'm, uh-- I'm looking forward
to reading it.
I'd be honored, Ellen.
But I can't take all the credit,
Josh brought so much
to the project.
Not really.
Mostly editorial stuff.
- Not true. Not true.
- It's more editorial stuff.
He's, really,
he's an inspiration.
No, it's all her.
(POLITE CHUCKLE)
What happened
to the sci-fi trilogy?
Ellen.
Uh, I haven't been
working on that for a while.
I've been meaning to tell you
how much I enjoyed
your short story.
Your short story.
It's a character study.
I haven't worked on it
in a while. Never finished it.
Well, it was
beautifully written, Josh.
Not really.
- It's old stuff, anyway.
- Old stuff?
Oh.
I'm gonna top this one off.
You wanna go make the rounds
a little bit?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
We're gonna--
I'm gonna go check
on the catering.
Yeah.
(LIGHT MUSIC PLAYS)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(CHATTERING)
(MAN) I am the most easygoing
person you'll ever meet.
Mind you, this neighbor comes
onto my property with a chainsaw
and cuts down the tree.
- Invasive roots, he says.
- Wow.
We're at a party. We're not
talking about the tree thing.
Yeah, but we got a case, right?
Um...
- That's, um, small claims.
- Yeah.
Rob and I do environmental law.
(ELLEN)
The moment has arrived, honey.
Speech time!
(ELLEN) How are we
gonna do this?
- (PAUL) I don't--
- Hello. Hello, hello.
I'm not gonna use this thing.
I don't think so.
(TAPPING GLASS)
Thank you all for being here
for our very special day.
And thank you, family
and friends, for coming out.
And the usual suspects
for coming out.
(CHUCKLING)
But most of all
we're so grateful, Paul...
- to have our kids here with us.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
Cynthia, Anna, Josh, Birdie...
love you guys.
We love you, Mom.
- Paul?
- Hmm?
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
My greatest happiness in life...
is being your wife.
(WOMAN) Aww.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
- (APPLAUSE)
(ANNA) Another round!
(APPLAUSE)
Cheers, Mom.
Um, uh...
- I'd-I'd like to--
- Oh!
Wow.
Yeah.
(SCATTERED CHUCKLES)
(MAN) Go for it, Paul.
You got it, Dad.
Uh...
I started out working as a...
broke Sous Chef
on the lower east side.
And, uh, I knew a guy...
who could sneak me into
the Museum of Modern Art.
(LAUGHING)
So I took him up on it.
And one day, I came upon this...
this...
this beautiful girl...
in the gallery...
in front of Rene Magritte's
"The Lovers".
Hmm.
And this girl, she was
breathing in this painting
like it was part of her.
And I thought, if I can get this
girl to look at me like that...
that would be a good life.
And she did.
And it's a great life.
Aww.
Ellen, you...
(SCATTERED CHUCKLES)
...you are my love,
you are my history...
and I am so in love with you.
(CHUCKLES, SNIFFLES)
I love you, darling.
(LAUGHING)
(APPLAUSE, CHEERING)
So cheers to 25 years.
(GLASS CLINKING)
(PAUL) And cheers to us.
Cheers to all of us!
- Yeah!
- (APPLAUSE)
(JOSH) Cheers.
Cheers.
(PEOPLE WHISTLE)
(ELLEN) Birdie.
Cheers.
(ANNA) Birdie.
(ELLEN) Everybody! Cheers!
(UPBEAT MUSIC STARTS)
("NESSUNO" BY MINA PLAYING)
(ELLEN LAUGHING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
I wasn't sure if you'd
remember me, Professor Taylor.
I didn't want to presume.
I didn't at first,
but I remember you now.
Josh has been anxious
about this.
We've been trying to find
the right time to tell you.
At my anniversary party?
- That was-- That was his idea.
- Oh.
I'm sorry, I didn't come here
to upset you.
Well, then I won't be upset.
I understand how it must look,
but I came here
with the best intentions.
What do you want, Elizabeth?
Your son and I
have a close attachment.
Right, it's all coming back.
The skillful way
you evade questions.
He loves me.
(CYNTHIA) You're good!
- ("NESSUNO" CONTINUES)
- (SISTERS GIGGLE)
You're very persuasive,
aren't you?
Regardless
of what you think of me,
I don't want to be the reason
things change in this family.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
I think you underestimate
my family.
This isn't going the way
that I'd hoped.
We'd hoped, I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MUSIC FADES)
("DONT DREAM IT'S OVER"
BY CROWDED HOUSE PLAYS)
Paul! I love this one.
- I know that.
- (ELLEN LAUGHS)
(CHATTERING)
It's kind of nice out,
the temperature.
Come on, let's go.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
You guys need a light? Ooh!
Yo, shhh!
- (CYNTHIA SQUEALS)
- (ELLEN CHUCKLES)
♪ Hey now, hey now,
Don't dream it's over ♪
Honey, I am exhausted.
I'm going upstairs.
You're gonna miss the best part.
I know.
♪ They come, they come ♪
(MUSIC CONTINUES MUFFLED)
(PHONE TICKING)
(BIRDIE CHUCKLES)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(CYNTHIA) Anna, you don't have
any boots. Who has boots?
- (JOSH) Yeah, I got.
- (ANNA) What do you have?
- (ANNA) Let me see it.
- (JOSH) I got.
(ANNA) You have something?
What do you have? Let me see it.
(ROB) Cynthia, would you let me
have a kit in the house?
(JOSH) You're so annoying!
Why would you say fucking--
- Okay. Hey.
- Mmm.
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
I've wanted to play drums,
but Cynthia won't let me
have a kit in the house.
Rob, I can hear you.
(LAUGHS)
Um... Rob and I are representing
the city of Baltimore
in a case against
the fossil fuel industry.
- Sounds like rewarding work.
- It is.
Except, the ocean is littered
with paperwork
and bureaucracy
and it all feels so...
- transgressive, you know?
- Mmm.
- You want some?
- Oh, no. I'm good.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Really?
- Yosh.
- Sorry?
You just seem
a little uptight, Liz.
Did I say something to--
Just...
Come on, we don't bite.
Sure, you do.
Would you chill out?
You're such a dick
since you got famous.
(LAUGHS) Yeah, that's fucking...
That is fucking priceless coming
from you, depression beard.
(CHUCKLES) Moping around ever
since you got turned down...
by every single publisher.
Right?
So you just--
You'll be a ghostwriter...
and you'll keep taking
Mommy and Daddy's money...
for your 400 square foot sublet
in Yorkville?
(WHISPERS) She's kind of right.
(LAUGHS)
Better? Can I stay?
We're glad you're here, Liz.
(WAVES LAPPING)
I'm fucking with you, Josh.
Come on. I'm sorry. I'm kidding.
Thanks.
Okay!
What the fuck are you doing?
- I'm gonna get my tits out.
- You out of your fucking mind?
- I'm jumping in.
- No, no, no, no, Rob.
- We going in?
- No.
(ANNA SHOUTING, SHRIEKS)
(SPLASHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING, LAUGHING)
(ROB) Jesus!
(DOG BARKS IN DISTANCE)
The kids found our weed stash.
(ELLEN) I need to tell you
about our son's new girlfriend.
- Liz.
- Mmm.
- Elizabeth Nettles.
- She's a former student.
- (GROANS)
- Wait, what? Josh's Liz?
- (LAUGHS) Yeah.
It's been eight years.
I didn't recognize her.
She's different now. I don't
know, more poised or something.
Is this where you tell me
that you had an affair
with our son's hot girlfriend?
Jesus, Paul, I'm being serious.
(LAUGHING)
She was a gifted student.
She was just...
radical in her ideology.
- Radical?
- Yes.
Supportive of acts
to subordinate...
to the point of
denigrating the Constitution.
I-Is it possible
that you're more distressed
about her having sex with
our son in the guest bedroom?
(SCOFFS) Paul, I don't think
it's a coincidence
that she's attached herself
to Josh.
- They were introduced.
- Mmm.
- By their agent?
- Wait, wait, wait.
Wait, you think that
she did this on purpose?
- Why-- Why would she do that?
- Because. I don't know.
Honey, she's probably
as uncomfortable
- as you are right now. Hell.
- (SCOFFS)
You don't know her, okay?
And what did she say? They're
writing some book together now?
How did she describe it?
"Our world through a new prism."
Very important.
- (SCOFFS)
- (PAUL CACKLES)
Christ.
It's all rushing back now.
All her draconian assertions
in my classroom.
- (PAUL LAUGHS)
- I dug up her thesis paper.
I found it to be dangerous
and inflammatory
for its anti-democratic
sentiments.
(PAUL GROANS)
"The Change:
Birth of a New Nation."
It advocates for a single-party
system for national unity.
What? Why are you smiling?
You called her out.
It was a debate!
Oh, so you called her out
in front of the whole class.
(SCOFFS)
It's Academia.
She's free to present any view.
I pushed back,
and she accused me of being
"bullying and belittling,"
so I reached out to my
colleagues, including the Dean.
I wasn't going to let her
just highjack my class.
Why are you minimizing this?
You basically described
every college student ever.
They're all a bunch of
little Mussolinis. They don't--
- (EXHALES)
- (VOICES OUTSIDE)
- (CYNTHIA) Let me out!
- (LAUGHING)
- (ITEMS CLATTER)
- (PLAYFUL SHOUTNG)
Eight years. People change.
No, Paul, they don't.
I was registered "no party
preference" when we met.
That is so not the same thing.
I'm just saying
that I don't think that
you have anything
to worry about,
because it's not gonna last.
Why are you trying
to spoil our night?
Don't do that!
- Oh! Oh!
- (CHUCKLES)
There she is, the naughty co-ed.
Guess how much
the Harris's home's worth?
- I don't know.
- It's in Forrest Hill.
(CYNTHIA) 2.5.
(ROB) Four million.
Why do you do this to yourself?
It's what all Americans do
in their spare time:
seethe in anger.
That's because you
don't have faith in anything.
What?
(CYNTHIA) Hmm?
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
That tree is definitely
obstructing
the neighbor's property.
See?
(GIGGLES)
How could anyone mistake you
for somebody who cares
about the environment?
Well, what do you want me to do?
Sit here while your sister
bangs the drummer upstairs?
I can't hear anything.
Here, take your vitamins.
(SIGHS)
Ironically, they sound like
the snare and high-hat.
- What are you talking about?
- Listen.
- (THUMPING UPSTAIRS)
- (IMITATES DRUMS)
- (WHISPERS) Listen.
- Shh.
What?
(MUFFLED GIGGLING)
Wait,
I think that's your parents.
(EXHALES)
(WHISPERS) Hey.
- Can we do quiet time? Shh.
- What? I'm quiet.
Shh. It's your breathing.
- It's like... yeah.
- Okay.
(THUD)
(PAUL)
Taylors, 10 minutes to go!
(ELLEN) Birdie, let's go!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
"Speak the speech,
I pray you...
as I pronounce it to you."
(GULLS SQUAWK)
(CYNTHIA) Can we go back now?
(ROB) Yeah, I think we're--
Look at the birds.
(CYNTHIA)
My God, what are you doing?
(LAUGHING)
(CYNTHIA)
Why did you just do that?
- Stop being stupid.
- (ROB) I'm not doing anything.
(CHATTERING)
Josh, can I talk to you
for a sec?
- We gotta make the 12:45.
- Yeah, I know.
(CYNTHIA) I'm scared! I don't--
(ROB) Just look at it.
Just look at it.
- (OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE)
- (BIRDS TWEETING)
Look,
I know what you're gonna say.
- Did she tell you everything?
- Yeah, she did. She did.
Not at first, 'cause
she figured I'd freak out.
But once we got serious,
she was honest with me.
(ELLEN SIGHS)
I probably could have
handled this better,
but, you know,
if you give her a chance,
I really think
you might like her.
She's really brilliant, Mom.
And she really looks up to you.
Honey, I don't think you're
grasping the gravity of it.
The gravity of it?
For who? She was the one
who had to leave Georgetown.
No, that was her choice.
Well, because
she was ostracized.
She felt like a pariah.
She was protected as a student.
Okay.
You know, I read it, the thesis?
And?
- It was provocative, sure.
- (GASPS)
But anti-democratic?
- Absolutely not. No.
- Yes!
Hostile to the theories
and policies of democracy.
Okay.
(DOOR SLAMS)
(SIGHS) I think that's
your generation talking.
The one that failed
its obligations?
The world's changed, Mom. Okay?
Someone's gotta bridge the gap.
Fuck, I promised
I wouldn't talk about this.
What are you talking about?
Promised who?
Can you just stop
for one second,
please, and be my mother?
What?
When did you ever need
my approval?
Is this about the novel?
Stop it with the goddamn novel.
It's a piece of shit.
Okay?
It's derivative sci-fi bullshit.
Nobody cared for a reason.
You are a talented writer!
No, I'm not, Mom!
I'm really fucking not!
I'm your son.
So, can you just treat me
like your son?
Instead of like one of
your fucking students, please?
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry
I'm not like my sisters,
you know,
who fucking excel at everything.
- Why do you do that?
- Drives you insane, doesn't it?
When have I ever made you
feel like a student?
(WHISPERS) You're doing it
right now! Right now!
What do you even know
about this girl?
Okay.
What do you know
about this girl?
(JOSH) You know what
drives you fucking crazy?
It's that you couldn't
bend her your way, right?
'Cause she thinks
for her fucking self. That's it!
Either that or that your son's
a failure. I don't know.
It's one of the fucking two.
- I gotta go.
- What?
- Catch your train, Josh.
- Yeah.
(ANNA) Obviously. You're coming
to my show in September, right?
Honey, we would not miss the
opportunity to have our family
excoriated
before a paying audience.
Use everything, right?
You taught me that, right?
- Be good.
- No. (LAUGHS)
- You all right?
- Mm-hmm.
Fine. Don't worry about me.
(INHALES)
Promise me you'll check in
from the road more often.
Yes, Scout's honor, Mom.
- (CYNTHIA) Mama, I love you.
- Oh, baby girl. (KISSES)
- Drive safe.
- I love you, too.
You text me everything
these fucking freaks do.
Are you for surreal?
(ELLEN) Love you, Rob.
Text when you get there.
- (PAUL) Josh!
- Bye!
All right, car's here. Love you.
(FOOTSTEPS)
- (JOSH) Sorry, sorry.
- (PAUL) Yup, yup.
- (PAUL GRUNTS)
- (JOSH SIGHS)
(ENGINES START, DEPART)
(SIGHS)
(CLOCK TICKING)
Anniversary gift.
From the both of us.
Oh, no, that's unnecessary.
We said no gifts.
That's very thoughtful of you.
Thank you, Liz.
I'm so glad you could join us
this weekend.
Look forward
to seeing you again.
Thank you.
Let's go, Bird is the word.
You know,
I used to be afraid of you.
But I don't think I am anymore.
We all know that the university
is a nest--
John, offer
all the platitudes you like...
about the pervasiveness
of liberalism
in the university,
but the campus is no monolith.
I think you're being naive,
Ellen.
- (ELLEN) Do you?
- We all know--
I don't know where
you went to school, John,
but the professors I know
tend to
encourage their students
to look at the evidence
and adjust their thinking
to that.
(HOST) And that, I'm afraid,
is all the time we have left.
Thank you, professors.
We will see you all.
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
(UNDER BREATH)
Oh, my God!
What? No, no, no, no, no.
(SCOFFS, CHUCKLES)
Look at you.
(SCOFFS, LAUGHS)
Oh, yeah.
Since the colonization
of America,
the Cumberland Company
has envisioned the ideals...
of a singular, national harmony.
Today, we are proud to partner
with visionary author
Elizabeth Nettles,
whose latest work
The Change ...
details the path back
to American solidarity.
(MUFFLED APPLAUSE)
Join the nationwide movement
that aspires to put United
back in these States of America.
We are the Cumberland Company.
U.S.A.!
(MAN) Your book The Change
is a cultural phenomenon.
Why is that?
(LIZ) Look, Americans feel
betrayed by the current system.
- They're tired of fighting.
- (MAN) Hmm.
(LIZ) The Change puts people
over politics.
(MAN) Yeah, but how?
(LIZ) Imagine a world
without political parties
that divided us into those
on the left or the right
or ultimately those above
and below.
(MAN) But that sounds
like one-party system.
(LIZ) No, no,
absolutely the opposite.
The essence of democracy,
no party system...
people who are
in the center of things.
I mean, look at the flag,
you know?
People united in togetherness,
gentleness.
Listening to others, caring
for others. The change ...
- (CYNTHIA) Hi!
- (PAUL) Thanks, sweetie.
Hi, sweetie.
Darling, I thought you couldn't
get the earlier flight!
Mom! (CHUCKLES) Hi.
Gemma worked it out.
She's my new assistant.
You know,
she used to be a recruiter
for a religious cult
in Montana,
- so she can be very persuasive.
- (CHUCKLES)
Can never tell
when you're joking.
It smells amazing in here.
Dad's making
his famous stuffing.
- (ELLEN SIGHS)
- Sage from the garden.
Well, it's a good thing
I got the run in. (CHUCKLES)
Well...
Yeah, I'll just go upstairs
and take a shower,
and then I'll be back down
and in everybody's way. (LAUGHS)
(AWKWARD CHUCKLE CONTINUES)
(WHISPERS) That was weird.
- Dad?
- Yeah?
She okay?
Your mother? She's fine.
(CYNTHIA) She doesn't seem fine.
Well, she's taking on a lot
at the university, so--
Come on, Dad, you know
what we're talking about.
What-- What the hell was that?
We're not gonna
do this today, okay?
Let's just try to enjoy the day.
Please.
Mom's been smoking
in her office.
Birdie, she's not.
(ENGINES REV OUTSIDE)
(ROB) Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, wait a second.
Are you kidding?
This is-- Wait, what?
- Good to see you.
- Check it out.
(ROB) Hey, this is
the sickest car I've ever seen.
(LOW CHATTER)
(ROB) Holy...
(DOOR CLOSES)
(ANNA) I'm in peacock pose,
and this gym bro
next to me, he says
"You know, I think
I really need to talk to you
about your set
on a woman's right to choose."
And I was like,
"Yeah, sure, buddy, of course.
As soon as the government
fucking castrates you,
then we can start having
a conversation about--"
That's enough.
No politics at the table,
remember? That's the rule.
- Since when?
- How about a preview
of the upcoming show?
That would be nice.
Well, sorry, Dad.
It's all political.
- Nice try.
- Thank you.
The acceleration's insane.
It fucking flies.
Mind if I ask how much
it set you back?
(QUIETLY) They gave it to us.
Shit you not. That's what
10 million copies sold gets you.
- I have an announcement.
- (ANNA) Huh?
- We booked the Beacon Theatre.
- (ANNA SCOFFS)
Hey! Congratulations.
- (ANNA) Hey, thank you.
- Hey, that one's a keeper.
Very diplomatic, Father.
Now she will want equal pay.
- Congrats.
- Thank you.
(PAUL) Hey. We're very proud
of you, both your mother and I.
(ANNA) Thank you.
- Yes, we are.
- (ANNA) Thank you, Mom.
The theater is fucking great.
I love it. I love the Beacon.
(QUIETLY) You and Cynthia
should really consider
what's going on, you know?
Yeah, no, we've, um,
definitely been discussing it.
- Okay, good.
- Mm-hmm.
'Cause it's a movement now.
Because it's beyond
just the book at this point,
you know?
(WHISPERS) We're working
with the Cumberland Company.
- The Cumberland Company?
- Mm-hmm.
(WHISPERS) Are you fucking her?
Cynthia she's my assistant.
- Of course I'm fucking her.
- You never learn.
- (GEMMA) When are you due?
- Oh, end of next month.
My ob-gyn thinks
they're identical.
- Really?
- Mmm.
- Do twins run in your family?
- No, not at all.
Crazy.
That's why we could hardly
believe it when they told us.
(JOSH CHUCKLES)
(BIRDIE) It's 0.45%.
What?
Uh, the odds of having
identical twins.
- (CHUCKLE)
- Mmm.
- (ANNA) That's our Birdie.
- It's an anomalous event.
(ANNA) She's like
an Encyclopedia Britannica.
Lucky us.
(ANNA) Where the hell
did she come from?
- (CYNTHIA) Who knows?
- (GEMMA) Good luck to you.
(LIZ) This stuffing
is delicious, Paul.
I can't stop eating it.
I'd love to give the recipe
to our chef.
Mmm. That's a great idea.
(PAUL) Thank you very much.
- (ANNA) Chef?
- I'll email it to you.
- Thank you.
- (JOSH) Thanks, Dad.
(CHUCKLES)
Thanksgiving.
Wow. Right?
I mean,
our heritage is so important.
(QUIET PIANO MUSIC PLAYS)
I just can't wait for the babies
to celebrate with us.
- Me, too.
- Mm-hmm.
The colonizers were actually
wolves in sheep's clothing
who brought smallpox blankets
and a deadly plague that
ravaged the Indigenous people.
Hell yeah, Birdie! Yes. Up top.
- (CYNTHIA LAUGHS)
- Right on. Up top, Baby Bird.
Not to mention racist as fuck,
but, you know, tradition.
(PAUL) Anna, all right, come on.
That's enough. Behave.
Okay, that's enough.
Come on, please.
(ANNA) No, come on,
tradition, Dad.
Turkey and genocide.
- That's enough.
- I didn't mean it like that.
(ANNA) No, I'll just fucking
censor myself. No big deal.
No, Bird!
Bird, where are you going?
Birdie!
(PAUL) Birdie, come back. She's
not laughing at you, honey.
Bird, she wasn't
talking about you.
Honey, we agree with you.
- Mom, should I go get her?
- No. It's something else.
If I could just interrupt
for a sec. Um...
Sorry, I'm cheers-ing with water
'cause we're drinking water.
Uh, we've got
some exciting news.
Oh, my God, you're pregnant!
Anyway, moving on.
That's hilarious.
That's very funny.
No, um... (CLEARS THROAT)
My brilliant wife
has been invited
to be a guest lecturer
at Georgetown.
(LIGHT GASP)
Liz, Josh, we're all very proud
of your success.
It's great for you.
And Ellen and I are delighted
that we're about
to become grandparents.
(DEEP EXHALE)
Ellen, I'd be honored
if you would do
the introduction for me.
(LIGHT EXHALE)
(QUIETLY) Is this a joke?
Oh, no, Mom. Autocracy
hates a sense of humor.
I'm sorry, what's your problem?
What's your problem?
- (JOSH) My problem?
- Yeah.
(STAMMERS) I'm sharing news
that I thought was positive.
You've just been gloating
ever since you got--
Why can't you let him
make a toast?
Why are you being
such a dickhead, Rob?
(PAUL) That's enough, all right?
(CYNTHIA) I can have
a conversation with my brother.
I'm not gonna sit here and watch
my family rip each other apart--
- Paul.
- No, Ellen, it's too much.
We're gonna act civilized.
We're here together.
- Let's try to enjoy it, please.
- Shut up, Paul.
(ANNA LAUGHS)
Wow. Holy shit.
- I find it...
- (ANNA GIGGLING)
ironic...
that you expect us to celebrate
your Frankenstein creation
today.
Published by a think tank
in the book business?
What better way to peddle
the Wonder-Bread-ification
of the policies
that they promote.
As palatable as a chef's version
of a baloney sandwich.
- (JOSH) Right, well...
- Liz, you wrote a book?
- Yes.
- (ANNA) Oh, boy, did she.
Yeah, a nice big one,
made 'em lots of money.
- What is it, The Change?
- Yes.
- You wrote The Change?
- Every word.
I didn't speak
to my parents for 12 years,
and then I read your book.
- Saved my life.
- Thank you, Gemma.
You're the reason I wrote
The Change.
(SCOFFS)
(QUIETLY) I wasn't joking about
the cult in Montana, by the way.
See, Mom, just a...
perspective outside your own,
that's all.
- I teach perspectives.
- You teach your perspective.
- Oh.
- If you can't be open-minded,
can you at least pretend
to be happy for us?
- For a second?
- Josh, I love you.
And you and your wife are doing
very well for yourselves
with your new occupation,
but you're nothing more
than bagmen
for the Cumberland Company.
Bagmen?
(CHUCKLES)
Wow.
I just find it fascinating
how exhausting
just how much strain
it takes for you to diminish--
No, going out of your way
to diminish...
- Josh.
- Josh, don't--
...success that anyone has
outside of yourself.
Can't you see that
the book is a weapon?
Yahoos on the Hill are already
fundraising off of it.
You know that they're hanging
flags and normalizing it?
It's the people
who are making the change.
- That's democracy.
- (QUIETLY) Oh, fuck's sake.
No.
You're engineering it.
(JOSH) Well, I'm not sure
when my own family
became a fascist regime,
but in case you forgot,
my wife's about to give birth
to your grandchildren.
Oh, my God, Josh.
A-plus for Liz.
(SCOFFS)
Well executed.
Do you hear yourself right now?
Please tell me
what reciprocal debt I owe
that will stop you
from poisoning my son.
- Holy shit, Mom!
- Jesus, Ellen,
she's eight months pregnant.
You should've read the book,
Paul.
No, I'm not gonna read the book.
I'm never gonna read the book,
because if I did,
I'd have to discuss it with you.
(CYNTHIA)
Whose side are you on, Dad?
There are no sides!
- There are sides. Clearly.
- (PAUL) There are no sides.
- (VOICES OVERLAPPING)
- (GRUNTING, GASPS)
There are no sides.
They're like
some united literary jihad.
Literally.
Gemma, that's funny.
Write that down.
- That goes in the show.
- (GROANS)
- Is she in labor?
- No, she's not in labor.
- It's the stress.
- (EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
(JOSH) You want to get some air?
We're gonna get some air.
(LOW CHATTER)
She knew exactly what she
was doing when she said that.
- Acting-- (LOUD) Hi, Mom.
- (ANNA) It was fucking crazy.
Hi, Mama.
Josh said that
they're gonna leave tonight.
- Going for a swim.
- What?
- In November, Mom?
- Fucking global warming.
(CYNTHIA) What the hell? What
happened to family Scrabble?
(JOSH) It's changed lives.
It changed mine.
(SIGHS)
They got Rob. Watch out.
I'm gonna need a new assistant.
- Yeah, no shit.
- (SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
Rob really wants
to start a family.
Really?
Yeah, really.
Really, really badly.
- That's all he talks about.
- What do you want?
Funny, I don't really have
an urge to reproduce.
- You know?
- (ANNA) Yeah. I know that.
You think that makes me selfish?
Uh, fuck no,
that does not make you selfish.
I do think you might be
a little depressed, though.
Roast him a chicken, give him
a blow job. He'll be fine.
(KNOCKING)
Hey.
I just want to make sure
you're okay before we go.
You guys are leaving?
Wow.
Huh.
You're very committed.
It's like
a real laboratory in here.
You know,
I wanted to be a scientist
before I changed majors.
Why did you change?
I realized
I wanted to make a difference.
Science makes a difference.
Sure.
It's growing in the Potomac.
Toils until it can find
a new host to attach itself to.
That's how it blossoms and
infects the entire ecosystem.
I could probably hook you up
with a password
for the archives from GVN.
You have access
to the Global Virus Network?
Sure. Here. Give me your phone.
Now we can talk
whenever we want.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
- (BIRDIE) Dad!
- (CYNTHIA) Birdie, you okay?
- Where's Dad? Dad!
- Birdie, what's going on?
Where's Dad?
Dad! Where's Mom?
She's having a swim.
You're scaring everybody.
What's going on?
Just tell us what's happening.
Look!
(PAUL) Oh.
Jesus, is that your mother?
Oh, shit.
(NERVOUS CHUCKLE)
Shut it off.
Whoever sent that to you,
tell 'em to take it down
right now.
- (BIRDIE) I can't.
- What do you mean you can't?
- It's online. It's everywhere.
- (JOSH) Fuck.
What's wrong with you people?
Oh. Thanks, Gemma.
Real great input.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hey, Ma.
(RAGGED BREATH)
- (GROANS)
- (LIQUID GUSHES)
- (JOSH) Oh, baby, baby, baby.
- Oh, fuck!
- (CYNTHIA) It's pee, isn't it?
- (JOSH) You okay, baby?
- (PAUL) Mount Vernon Hospital.
- (SCREAMING)
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Okay, we got to go
to the hospital.
Mount Vernon Hospital.
I'll drive.
No, I got it. I got it.
Cynthia,
I'm gonna follow them, okay?
Go, Rob!
- (JOSH) I got it, I got it.
- I can drive you. I'll drive.
- (PAUL) Don't worry about it.
- (DOOR SLAMS)
I'm sorry. (GASPS)
(EXHALES)
(KNOCKING)
Uh...
- Hi, Birdie.
- Hi.
My house has gone insane.
(SCOFFS)
Oh, my parents invited you
for dinner Saturday night.
Oh, yeah.
Sure, that sounds great.
Yeah, you shouldn't come.
- Why?
- Full disclosure?
They'd never say it
to your face,
but they don't like it
when we hang out.
My mom's been having
terrible nightmares
'cause you don't figure
into her life plan for me.
Plus your, uh--
Your sister-in-law
wrote that book, which
stirs up all kinds of trauma
for them.
Oh.
- Uh, what's this for?
- Wha-- Oh.
You never know when and where
violence is gonna escalate.
I've taken 1,800 volleys of
tear gas and 900 rubber bullets.
(GRUNTS)
Yeah, that's cool.
Yeah, I know.
(GRUNTS)
- (CLATTERING)
- (GASPS)
- (GRUNTS)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
(LAUGHS)
(DOG BARKING)
(DOGS BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(MAN) Hey!
- Hey, what's going on?
- Oh, shit!
Go! Go! (GIGGLES)
(PAUL) Okay, thanks.
Bye, honey.
Well...
that was Cynthia.
Liz is not in labor.
The ER doctor said
that it was a, uh,
it was a hysterical bladder.
- (SIGHS)
- Oh, come-- (LAUGHS)
(SNIFFS)
You have every right
to be upset.
It was a long, ugly day.
I barely remember his childhood.
I mean,
I was building my career, and...
- he was needy.
- (EXHALES)
I mean, he was...
he was never interested
in the restaurant.
He was always with you.
Your little pet project.
There was a synthesis
between you. We all felt it.
Synthesis?
Ellen, your daughter-in-law
is giving a lecture
at Georgetown, your campus.
Why is it that you can't
swallow your pride
- and just introduce her?
- The message...
is very convincing.
It terrifies me.
You don't do well
with uncertainty,
and guess what,
that's all there is right now.
I'm tired. I don't
want to talk about it anymore.
How bad is it?
Would you like me to be honest?
Yes.
CNN is running it on a loop.
Christ!
Oh, my God, it's so humiliating.
It's a flag.
What were you thinking?
Please don't call it that.
And it was involuntary.
I don't know what came over me.
Flag bad. Oh, God!
Maybe we get out of here
a few days, just the two of us.
(CHUCKLES, GROANS)
Drive up to that place we love
in Kennebunkport.
Eat some lobster rolls,
drink too much sauvignon blanc.
Oh.
- Come here, you.
- Mmm.
We have to call the attorney.
- Ellen.
- What?
(QUIETLY)
Everything is going to be okay.
(EXHALES)
(MAN)
The old order is finally gone.
On behalf of America,
we wanted to thank you
for choosing The Change.
You joined
the greatest movement
in the history of our nation.
There's nothing more sacred
than freedom.
By becoming The Change , you
decided to regain your freedom
restore your dignity,
and recapture your destiny.
We are one united movement.
(WOMAN)
We are one united people.
(MAN) We are one
United States of America.
(WOMAN) We are The Change.
(MAN) We are The Change.
This is our moment.
The future belongs to us.
(CHEERING)
How do you like that one?
Thank you. Yeah.
You know
what they're calling it?
They're calling it
a restoration for America.
"Join us! Become
a card-carrying club member."
Critical thoughts, um,
no longer on the menu.
- (SPLASHING)
- (GASPING)
'Cause thinking has been
subbed out with
nausea-inducing pabulum
that could choke a cloned cow.
- (MAN) Fuck you!
- Oh, fuck you, too.
What, did I strike a chord
with my little joke?
- (SPLASHING)
- (GASPING)
Don't blame me.
It was that book.
- You all fucking bought it!
- (ANGRY SHOUTING)
Selling your own country out
for $32.99 on Amazon.
(GASPING)
They will come for the outspoken
and the intellectuals first.
That is what history books
teach us.
And you know what?
You're good. You are all safe.
(WOMAN) You're a piece of shit!
Don't come to my show
and expect not to get insulted.
Oh, you want your 15 seconds
and join me?
(CROWD SHOUTING)
You're the problem! You!
- (WOMAN) Get off me!
- You're the problem!
(SHOUTS)
(BIRDIE) That was my sister's
last performance.
(SOBBING)
(BIRDIE) She suffered
35 stitches, a concussion
and five days in the ICU.
That was six months ago.
She walked out
of Lenox Hill Hospital
and hasn't been seen since.
(GASPS)
(BIRDIE)
We didn't hear from Anna again.
Everything around us
is changing.
Acts of violence have
erupted all over the country.
- (SPEAKING GERMAN)
- Fear went mainstream.
The Internet is monitored,
and
they rationed the bandwidth.
The Tattleware app is installed
on millions of phones.
Neighbor turning in neighbor
with the flick of a slider.
Disinformation is everywhere.
Please help us find Anna.
And make this message viral
via secure portal.
(CYNTHIA) Happy birthday, Dad.
- Is that the new babysitter?
- (ELLEN) Au pair.
- "Au pair."
- Co-conspirator.
Eva Braun.
She speaks perfect German, which
the boys obey like Nazi youth.
- Hey, Mom.
- Hi, Rob.
(BIRDIE) My family will
freak out if they find out
we're looking for Anna
on the dark web.
They're gonna kill us.
Resist or die, right? (EXHALES)
You sound like
you're in a splendid mood.
Don't worry,
I promised I would play nice.
(EXHALES)
It's his birthday wish.
- (DOG BARKING)
- (BOYS GIGGLING)
(SIGHS)
Any word
from the private investigator?
Well, Anna still hasn't accessed
her credit card or phone,
which isn't good.
But there are a few new leads
which he is following, so...
that's-- that's hopeful.
Hmm.
- Hopeful.
- Can I talk to you?
I was just wondering,
maybe you could go back to work.
At a new college,
obviously, part-time.
Just something
to get your mind off things.
Honey, I'm on a watch list.
Are we sure about that?
It was clear from the appeal.
(BABIES CRYING)
- (JOSH) It's okay.
- (LIZ) Oh, honey, I know.
(JOSH) Gerda!
Can you please get in here?
(BABY WAILING)
You okay? It's okay.
I know.
I know. It's okay. It's okay.
(JOSH) Hey, Gerda,
can you come in here, please?
We need a tissue.
- Honey.
- (LIZ) Gerda?
I know. I know, honey.
(JOSH) Gerda?
Are you sure that's a good idea?
(WAILING CONTINUES)
It's okay. Hey.
(WAILING)
- Cynthia?
- Yeah?
I-I can't take this.
You want me to take it
out of the box?
- (WAILS)
- I know.
(JOSH) Gerda, can you get the--
All right, thank you.
(SCREAMING)
(BABY WAILING)
Somewhere where I can't hear
them screaming, Gerda, please.
- Jesus Christ.
- (GERDA MURMURS)
- I'm gonna check on the cake.
- Yeah, okay.
Sorry about that.
She seems, uh,
good with the kids.
Yeah, she came
highly recommended.
She's teaching the boys German,
French and Mandarin.
It's critical children
be multilingual.
Honestly,
we're lucky to have her.
(CYNTHIA) Mm-hmm.
- I'll go get the lighter.
- (LIZ) Okay.
- I'm glad we're doing this.
- (CLEARS THROAT)
The boys need to know
their grandparents.
- (HUFFS)
- Come on, stay outside.
(BARKS)
Birdie?
(EXHALES)
You're looking good, Dad.
You working out?
- That dog's keeping me fit.
- Oh, yeah, I bet.
What's the dog's name,
by the way?
Oh, we don't know.
We found him
in Anna's apartment.
We didn't even know
she had a dog.
So, what have you
been calling him?
Bird is the word.
- (WHISPERS) Hey.
- Hi.
- It's good to see you.
- You, too. How you doing?
(LIZ, CYNTHIA)
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
(ALL)
♪ Happy birthday, dear Dad ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
(CYNTHIA)
Wait, I'm gonna do a picture.
Come on.
(CHUCKLES)
Ah... Today is...
bittersweet.
We all miss Anna terribly.
(LIZ) For Anna.
(INHALES, EXHALES)
Do you want to
cut the cake, Mom?
- Sure.
- That was nice, hon.
(FORKS CLATTERING)
Birdie, I don't think
we've met your friend.
You want to introduce us?
Uh, yeah, this is Moses.
- Moses?
- (MOSES) Yeah.
I'm Josh. This is my wife Liz.
- Hi.
- I'm Birdie's older brother.
Yeah, I know. (EXHALES)
Moses just won
a scholarship to university.
Really? That's great.
What university?
Uh, Northwestern.
- Get the hell out of here!
- Josh went to Northwestern.
- Oh, no kidding?
- (JOSH) Yeah, I did.
It's a great school.
Congratulations.
You know what you're studying?
Uh, Journalism.
Journalism?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
Well, we certainly need
more qualified journalists.
Hear, hear.
Why journalism?
- Josh.
- Honey.
I'm asking him a question.
Why journalism?
I don't know, I...
(NERVOUS LAUGH)
I started writing
in the school paper--
He wrote an exposé
about the dangers of censorship.
I mean, you can't even shoot
a zombie in a video game anymore
without being labeled
subversive.
Protecting the freedom
of expression, human rights.
It's fantastic.
Good for you.
It's an admirable pursuit,
journalism.
Especially with the way
the world is now.
It's dangerous on
the front lines. It's no joke.
What happened to that journalist
a few years ago?
Got chopped up?
Right? What was it?
(ROB) The one
who went into the embassy
for a marriage license?
- Yes.
- Came out in little bags.
- Jesus.
- (JOSH) Chopped up.
Awful. Scary stuff.
Terrible thing.
I, uh, I should go.
- I should get going.
- Where are you going?
Uh, my mom's expecting me
back for dinner, so...
I'm sorry, I didn't mean
to make you uncomfortable.
- No, y-you didn't.
- If I did, sorry.
No, not at all. I-I ju--
My mom's just-- She gets ratty.
(JOSH)
If you want, I can drive you.
It's really no problem.
I don't mind.
We can finish our conversation.
The dangers of censorship
in video games.
- Um...
- (ELLEN) Moses,
tell your mom we said hi.
Happy birthday.
Nice to meet you.
(FOOTSTEPS DEPART)
- (EXHALES)
- (DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
The third degree
was unnecessary.
What's that?
I said the third degree
was unnecessary.
The third degree?
I thought we weren't gonna
do this anymore.
I was curious about journalism.
- That was the agreement, right?
- Right.
Kid wants to be a journalist.
(EXHALES)
Just trying to have
a conversation.
Josh. (SIGHS)
What-- What am I missing?
I don't know.
Was it a mistake coming here?
- Josh!
- Yeah?
(THUMPS TABLE)
We got it.
Okay.
(MOUTHING) Sorry.
Rob, what about you?
What's going on with the case?
The case...
is still a shit show.
- It's a disaster.
- (JOSH) I'm sorry to hear that.
Um, but...
Cynthia and I are pregnant.
- (JOSH) Seriously?
- (GASPS) Oh, my God!
- That's wonderful news!
- (ROB) Seriously. Yeah.
Congratulations!
(PAUL) Best birthday gift ever.
- Our kids are gonna be cousins.
- What are you doing?
It is early to announce it,
but we had some good news,
and I thought we could all do
with some good news.
Champagne, huh? Champagne.
No, I'm good. It's just...
we should've waited
'cause it's early.
I know.
(CYNTHIA)
We were planning on waiting...
- Birdie.
- ...a little longer.
Did you get a chance
to look at the stuff I sent you?
What stuff?
Birdie?
(STAMMERS)
There is an internship
at the Cumberland Company.
Birdie would be able to get
into any of the top university
virology programs
in the country.
It's highly competitive,
but I talked to the board,
and they're--
(UNDER BREATH)
Goddamn it!
(SIGHS) Birdie, go to your room.
I think
I can make my own decisions.
I'm sorry, Ellen.
I thought you'd be happy.
It's an excellent opportunity
for her.
(QUIETLY) Oh, shit.
Besides, what were you always
telling us as kids?
What was it?
"Follow the music we hear"?
(EXHALES)
If you try to groom
another one of my children,
I will kill you.
(RAGGED BREATH)
(KNIFE THUDS)
(FOOTSTEPS DEPART)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
- Oh.
- (SNIFFLES)
- I miss her.
- Mmm.
(WHISPERS) I miss her, too.
Cynthia, I said
that I was sorry, didn't I?
I think that we should go home.
- You want to go home?
- I'd like to go home.
- Yeah. Sure.
- Great.
- (ROB WHISPERS) Great.
You know, maybe you should
lay off the sleeping pills,
because I think...
I just think
they're messing with your head.
I fucking hate you.
- (LIGHT CLATTERING)
- (EXHALES)
Hey.
(JOSH EXHALES)
Liz is packing up the car,
so we'll be out of your hair
in a minute.
Mind if I join you for a sec?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
(EXHALES)
Turn this off.
I need a breather.
- Lot going on, huh?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
It's fucking constant.
(LIGHT CHUCKLE)
But I don't got to
tell you about that.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. How you holding up?
- I'm getting there.
- Mmm. Yeah.
- You know.
- Yeah, I know.
That's why I want to check.
Yeah.
I did want to mention to you,
actually, the boys...
seem to be running
a little temperature.
You didn't let 'em outside
earlier, did you?
Well, they had sweaters.
Just 'cause they
kind of get this ear thing--
Yeah, no, well,
children are a cause
for concern, aren't they?
- Yeah. I'm learning that.
- (CHUCKLES) Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
Got a lot to learn.
(SIGHS, CHUCKLES)
How's everything else?
How's the restaurant going?
- Restaurant?
- Hmm.
Well, you know,
palate's a fickle thing.
You got that right.
Tough business.
60% fold in the first year,
80 by year five. Right?
I wouldn't go near
that business model.
Yeah.
Well, you know,
that business model, though,
it put three kids
through college, didn't it?
(QUIETLY) You know,
I know about the foreclosure
that you had to...
stave off with the second
mortgage on the house,
the one Mom
doesn't know about.
Hmm.
(WHISPER) How your meat supplier
is squeezing you. You know?
Barely making payroll.
Your pastry chef's papering
the town with her résumé.
And that's your right hand.
Everyone knows that.
It's got to be tough.
A man must not be burdened
by the secrets he carries.
Hey.
You remember
when you were a kid?
How you loved canned
macaroni and cheese?
Yeah, of course.
Yeah, Franco-American.
It was the best.
That's right.
I tried to get you to
eat better, but you wouldn't.
You know why?
I don't know,
I loved the way it tasted.
You loved the way
it made you feel.
Food tells a story
that imprints memory.
That's why I do it.
(JOSH EXHALES)
That's why it's worth the risk.
I'm happy it makes you happy.
Listen, I want to come on
as a silent investor.
What do you think?
Totally hands-off.
You'll run the show.
Keep you afloat. You could even
do that remodel you wanted to.
Hey, what better way to
cultivate Beltway politicos,
huh?
I thought it was the coolest
birthday present I could offer.
(CHUCKLES)
(EXHALES)
We're the keeper
of our own souls.
(JOSH) Hmm.
Be careful.
You want to sleep on it?
- (PAUL) Hmm.
- You don't have to decide now.
You know what bothers me?
Anna.
Your sister.
You remember her?
She kind of bothers me, too.
(EXHALES)
She's a wandering libertine,
though. She did it to herself.
The embarrassment that
she must cause your new friends
over on K Street, huh?
Yeah, she's a bit of a headache.
Yeah.
And-- And so, is that
why you stopped by here today?
To, uh, offer me
this little bribe here?
(GIGGLES)
Bribe?
Or did you think
that I'd give up my daughter?
Wait, so does that mean
you know where she is?
Hey, Josh,
you should leave this house now.
(INHALES)
I think you know what's coming.
And a smart businessman
would listen.
Think about that.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Oh...
When I tell you to not let
my sons go outside,
I fucking mean it.
(RAIN PATTERING)
(BIRDIE) Whoo! It's really
coming down! Come on!
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
- (YELPS)
Oh, that's okay, Gerda.
I got it. Oh!
Oh. (EXHALES)
Hey, Mom. It's me.
I don't understand.
I'm sorry I haven't been able
to contact you before now,
but those fuckers are trying
to charge me with crimes
and brand me
an enemy of the state.
I just can't tell you
where I am. I'm sorry.
But, you know,
fucking Gerda's with us.
Isn't that some crazy spy shit?
I miss you, and I love you.
Give Bird a hug for me.
Tell Dad I miss his cassoulet.
Bye for now.
(GASPS, CHUCKLES)
(SOBS)
(BABIES SHRIEKING)
Where the hell have you been?
I'm sorry,
I was helping your mom.
Just get in the car, please.
The kids are losing
their fucking minds.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ROB) What podcast
do you want to listen to?
I know you think
that it's a miracle.
And I really thought
that I could, but I can't.
What are you talking about?
I terminated it last week.
I was gonna tell you.
I just needed some time.
And...
(ROB SCOFFS)
No, no, you...
I told you how I felt
over and over and over again.
Rob, I know that you're hurt,
but I'm not wrong.
It's not fair to bring a child
into this fucking situation.
No, Cynthia,
that's your depression talking.
- It's your depression talking.
- No, Rob.
It's why you need the pills.
It's why you need therapy.
It's God knows
what the fuck else.
Look... around us.
You shouldn't be having children
when the world
doesn't make any sense.
A kid doesn't make it
any better.
That was my life, too.
It-- It's gone.
(VOICE BREAKING)
I don't know who I am.
Can't you fucking see that?
That I'm just dead inside?
I'm a shell of a human being,
a shell of... (GASPS)
...someone
I think I'm supposed to be.
I don't live!
- That was my child.
- Your child?
- That was our child.
- How dare you?
Our child. I was gonna
be a fucking father.
- Get out of the car.
- Are you fucking--
Get out of the fucking car!
Get out of the car, Cynthia!
- Don't fucking touch me!
- Are you fucking crazy?
- Don't yell at me!
- Get the fuck out of this car!
- Don't you dare fucking--
- Are you fucking crazy?
- Don't touch me!
- You know what? Fuck this!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
- Rob, slow the fuck down!
- (ENGINE REVS)
- (ALARM BEEPING)
- (THUD)
(SUSTAINED BEEP)
Oh, fuck this. Fuck this.
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
Fuck! You little fuck!
(SHOUTS)
Fuck you! You fucking
ruined my fucking life!
Oh, fuck you! Oh, fuck!
What the fuck are you doing?
(SOBS)
Jesus! Please stop it!
That was my fucking baby!
(SOBS)
That was my fucking child,
Cynthia!
- Please, please, baby!
- (ROB) Why did you--?
Fuck you!
That was my fucking baby!
Baby?
- (ENGINE REVS)
- (CYNTHIA SCREAMS)
Where are you going?
Can you please--
(ENGINE ROARS)
Come back to me! (SOBS)
(GASPS) Ro--
(PANTING)
Dog.
You need a name, dog.
We both know
you couldn't afford to keep me.
Right.
I'm at Old Ebbitt Grill
in Lafayette Square.
You should come by sometime.
(VOICE CRACKS)
I'll make you a soufflé.
(RANA WHISPERS) Be careful.
They're targeting
the non-Changers in your area.
(DOG BARKS)
(ROCK MUSIC BLARES)
("RIP IT OUT"
BY HOTWAX PLAYING)
(MUSIC BLARES FROM BELOW)
(GRUNTS)
(ELLEN) Paul?
(DOG YELPS)
We should give the dog a name.
She's coming back for him.
(INHALES)
Don't you understand?
Nothing is the same.
We can't stop living.
Attention must be paid.
Otherwise, what is there?
I'm begging you, please,
Ellen, name the dog.
No.
Buster? Charlie? Freckles?
Just-- Just name the dog.
Just give the dog
a name, please.
Ellen, name the dog.
Name the dog.
Ellen, name the fucking dog.
Name the dog! Name the dog!
Name the fucking dog!
Name the dog!
Name the fuck-- Geez.
(SOBS)
Please, Ellen.
(GASPS) Just name the dog!
(BIRDIE) There were
no birthdays, holidays,
anniversaries or celebrations
the following year.
There's a new census
to track Americans.
Moses Ho and his parents fled,
just like hundreds of thousands
of journalists, scientists,
academics, intellectuals,
artists and free thinkers.
- (BULBS CLICKING)
- (TYPING)
My mom's found a purpose again,
using words to fight back.
(TAPPING)
(QUIETLY) Shit.
Paul. Paul.
That thing keeps happening.
With the electricity.
The computer's--
What?
The gate's open.
- (KNOCKING)
- (WOMAN) Mr. and Mrs. Taylor.
We've made numerous attempts
to contact you.
We're from the census.
(SHUTTER CLICKS)
(WHISPERS) Stick to the script.
We'll be fine.
You have a lovely home.
Thank you.
Mmm.
That's lovely.
Indonesian.
You know your beans.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, you'd be surprised by what
coffee reveals about people.
How so?
Well, for starters,
this coffee is refined,
like the two of you.
You drink it black-- efficient,
purist, resistant to change.
Your wife takes
a dollop of soy milk--
perfectionist,
stickler for rules and order.
(CHUCKLES)
Cream and sugar-- what does it
say about the both of you?
I suppose that makes us
people pleasers.
(CHUCKLES)
I have some things to attend to,
so if we could move this along.
How long have you been married?
Twenty-nine years.
How long have you lived
at this residence?
(PAUL) Twenty-eight years.
We moved here
when our oldest child was born.
How is she? Anna?
We haven't seen our daughter
since she went missing
two years ago.
(WOMAN 1) How many people
currently live in the home?
(PAUL) Four.
Who currently lives in the home?
Myself, my wife
and our two daughters.
The bureau database shows you,
your wife and three daughters.
- Incorrect.
- Cynthia Taylor, Birdie Taylor,
and Anna Taylor.
Please don't make this
infuriating.
Anna hasn't lived here
since she left for college.
Your database needs updating.
That's why we're here,
Mr. and Mrs. Taylor.
(CHUCKLES)
Do you have a current address
for your daughter?
No.
(WOMAN 1) Have you been
in contact with her?
- No.
- (WOMAN 1) Why not?
We already told you.
(WOMAN 2 LAUGHS)
Just that, you know,
your daughter is such a scream.
I mean,
some people took offense,
her being in the spotlight,
but I loved it. (CHUCKLES)
Before everything got
so political.
What is your political
affiliation?
Decline to answer.
- Under what dispensation?
- The Bill of Rights.
Both currently unemployed.
- Is that correct?
- Correct.
Your mortgage remains current.
May I ask
how you manage the payments?
Are we done
with this interrogation?
We're not here to...
attack you.
I was terminated
by the university.
My husband sold his restaurant
for us to survive.
Is there anything else?
Let me be frank,
Mr. and Mrs. Taylor.
Anna has not responded
or filled out her census.
If you are harboring her
or refusing to disclose
her whereabouts,
there will be no distinction
between yourselves
and her seditious actions.
So...
you need to decide
if you're with us or against us.
You recite old Bush Doctrine,
which makes you
both liars and plagiarists.
Your daughter can't run around
like Joan of Arc.
Joan of Arc's only crime was
standing up when others refused.
- A real saint.
- A witness.
Anna Agnes Taylor,
born May 3rd,
George Washington Hospital.
She came into the world hard,
an umbilical cord
wrapped around her neck twice.
A fighter. Current status?
Lovesick, hilarious, beautiful,
decent, unimpeachable.
Whereabouts? Go fuck yourselves!
We've already
filled out our census.
Now, please leave us alone!
Don't you understand
we've had enough?
There was a goddamn pipe bomb
in our mailbox.
(WOMAN 2)
Your youngest daughter.
It's not real.
We don't always know what
our children are capable of.
Seems Anna isn't the only rebel
in the family.
She's a child.
She's a science geek
who stays all day in her room.
(WOMAN 2)
Under the new security law,
she will be prosecuted
as an adult.
Twenty-year minimum
for conspiracy
to commit seditious acts.
All you have to do is sign here.
Become a Change Home.
If not, you leave us no choice.
We'll never sign that.
(TABLET THUDS)
(FOOTSTEPS RETREAT)
You are not to leave this house!
Do you hear me?
You are not to sneak out
anymore!
(SOBBING) I can't believe you!
Let me explain.
- Just let me talk to you, okay?
- (SCREAMING)
Fuck you!
(SOBBING)
With your fucking tail
between your legs!
- Please.
- (CRIES)
(BIRDIE) I don't know you.
(PHONE RINGING)
(PHONE BUZZES)
(ELLEN WHISPERS) You shouldn't
be outside after curfew.
Say something, please.
What choice did we have?
(SNIFFS)
We can leave.
We can-- We can take the girls
and-- and find Anna.
And go somewhere safe.
I'm sorry, Paul.
Let's leave.
(PHONE BEEPS)
(DRONE WHIRS)
(WOMAN VOICE) Attention.
To avoid violations, please
respect the curfew hours.
If you have any questions,
please contact the district
supervisor's office.
This is your second warning.
(CHATTERING)
I need to talk to you.
I have nothing to say to you.
You need to talk to Josh.
You have obliterated us.
What more do you want?
(GASPS) You have to help me.
Please. (RAGGED BREATHING)
I don't know who he is anymore.
What did you think
was going to happen?
(SNIFFLING)
I'm coming to you as a mother.
Please. Please.
Your husband, not my son.
(GASPS)
(SNIFFS)
(EERIE VOCALIZING)
(EERIE VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
(BRIGHT PARTY CHATTER)
- Hi, everybody. Hi.
- (WOMAN) Hi, Elizabeth.
- (WOMAN 3) Hi, Liz.
- (WOMAN 4) Good to see you.
- Hi.
- Hello, Elizabeth.
Hi, baby.
- You're a little late.
- Hi.
(TAPPING MICROPHONE)
(JOSH) Hello, everyone.
Thank you all for joining us
for this very special occasion.
My parents' 30th anniversary.
- Round of applause, please.
- (APPLAUSE)
- (WOMAN) Lovely.
- (JOSH) Thank you.
Now, I stand before you
this evening,
not only as a proud son,
but...
Liz? Can you come up here,
honey, please?
Liz, honey?
Will you join me up here,
please?
Think I can safely speak
for the both of us
when I say that we could not
have two better role models,
not just for our marriage,
but as parents to our children.
And as it has not always
been easy--
certainly not--
we love you guys.
Happy anniversary.
Now, if I can go off script here
a little bit,
I have a little surprise.
Can we cue the song?
("DON'T DREAM IT'S OVER"
BY CROWDED HOUSE PLAYS)
And if I may ask my parents
to please step forward
and share a dance to their song
as a celebration of their love.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Paul and Ellen Taylor!
(APPLAUSE)
(CHEERING)
Come on.
♪ There's a battle ahead ♪
♪ Many battles are lost ♪
♪ But you'll never see
The end of the road ♪
♪ While you're traveling
With me ♪
♪ Hey now, hey now,
Don't dream it's over ♪
♪ Hey now, hey now ♪
♪ When the world comes in ♪
♪ They come, they come ♪
♪ To build a wall between us ♪
♪ We know they won't win ♪
(HONKS HORN)
♪ There's a hole in the roof ♪
♪ My possessions
Are causing... ♪
(MUSIC STOPS)
- (JOSH) Who do we have here?
- (GUEST) Look at that.
(JOSH) Okay.
This is fun.
Uh, I-- This is a total surprise
to me. I didn't do it.
I'm sure I'm paying for it.
Hello.
- (HORN TOOTS)
- (MUSIC STARTS)
♪ Happy anniversary
Happy anniversary ♪
♪ Happy she and happy he ♪
♪ They're both as happy
As can be ♪
♪ Celebrating merrily
Their happy anniversary ♪
♪ Happy anniversary
Happy anniversary ♪
(JOSH) Okay. Everyone give it up
for the clown. That's fantastic.
I really didn't know that one
was coming. Moving forward.
I'm gonna pass the mic here
to the love of my life,
Elizabeth Nettles Taylor.
She has a few words to say
about the Cumberland Company.
Thank you, Josh, for your...
- (PANTING)
- (MUFFLED SPEECH CONTINUES)
(DOG YELPS)
Carlin.
I missed you, buddy.
Come on, we got to go.
Let's go.
Come on.
(KNOCKS)
Birdie?
Cyn?
(WHISPERS) Anna.
Hey. Hey.
(CYNTHIA GASPS)
Hey!
Hey, where-where's Birdie?
(WHISPERS) Where's Birdie?
(HORNS HONKING)
(EXHALES)
Hey, are you okay?
- What are you doing here?
- (GRUNTS)
Surprising Mom and Dad
for their anniversary.
It's their anniversary?
(LIZ) In a time that
has tested our resolve
and revealed our true nature,
we are correcting the course
for this country.
- Hear, hear!
- (APPLAUSE, CHEERS)
We are creating futures
for our families...
(MESSAGE BEEPS)
...and new educational
opportunities for our children.
(DISTANT APPLAUSE)
Where's Rob?
(WHISPERS) He's one of them now.
- Oh.
- They take everyone.
- (MUFFLED SPEECH)
- You shouldn't be here. Go. Go.
(CHATTERING)
(EXHALES)
And I'm excited to share
that because of our research
here at the Cumberland Company,
we are confident that our child
reeducation bill will pass.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
(CHATTER)
(MAN REPORTING) ... can confirm
there has been an attack
at the Cumberland Company
at approximately 5:00 p.m.
(CUP CLINKS ON TABLE)
(EXCITED CHATTER)
Stay inside.
(MAN REPORTING)
Law enforcement tells us that
a biological agent was released
inside the building, just
a mile from the White House.
As a proud mother myself,
I'm happy that my sons
will have a better community...
(PHONES BEEPING)
...that will provide them
with love--
Excuse me, Elizabeth?
(EXCITED CHATTER)
- (MAN) It's online, too.
- (WOMAN) It's for real.
Okay, we need to go.
We need to go right now.
Stand by.
We found a live stream
from the mobile phone
of the suspect
who may be an employee
with the company.
(LIGHT GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(SOBS)
(SCATTERED CHATTERING)
(SOBBING)
(CHATTERING)
- (SNIFFLING) Hey, hey.
- (SOBBING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
(SOBBING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
- She's here.
- (CRYING)
(RAGGED BREATH) I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
(RAGGED BREATHING)
- Okay.
- Josh.
(BLOW LANDS)
(CHUCKLES)
(SCOFFS)
(SIRENS WAIL IN DISTANCE)
(GROANS)
(SIREN WAILS)
Drop the weapon!
Put your arms up!
Hey, drop it or I'll shoot!
Repeat, drop the weapon!
(GUNSHOTS FIRE)
- (GASPING)
- (ANNA) Dad.
Dad!
- (QUIETLY) Run.
- Run! Run!
- (ELLEN) Run!
- (ANNA) Dad! Dad!
Dad! Mom!
Run!
Run! Run!
(OFFICER) Get down now!
Stop!
Don't move!
Go!
(GASPING)
- She's here, she's here!
- Freeze!
(GASPING)
(MACHINE GUN FIRE)
(PAUL STRAINING)
(GASPING)
- (ELLEN) I'm so scared. Paul.
- Listen to my voice.
Check the house.
- Clear!
- (JOSH) Officer.
You in charge of this unit?
Back door is clear!
Are you leading this unit?
(PAUL) I can see you.
Beautiful girl standing
in front of that painting.
Can you see her?
(ELLEN) I don't know.
(PAUL) Try. (GASPS)
Look hard. Try.
I see us.
Just, uh,
they're my parents in there,
so I don't want them separated.
I want to keep them together.
You understand me?
I hope there's not
a problem, sir.
(QUIETLY) There's not a problem.
(WHISPERING) I'm your superior,
and you need to listen
to what I'm telling you.
You understand?
Why don't you back up?
Do you know who the fuck I am?
Don't fucking touch me!
You know who I fucking am? Huh?
You know who I fucking am?
(SHOUTS)
Fuck you! (GROANS)
Wait, that's my family.
That's my family! (VOICE BREAKS)
That's my family!
That's my family! Please!
Ma'am.
(JOSH STRUGGLING)
Take him, too.
(RAGGED BREATHING)
- He's with them.
- Yes, ma'am.
(GROANS, WHIMPERS)
(EXHALES)
(RAGGED BREATHING)